<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<studyGuide version="1.1" locale="en">
  <series title="Divine Flow — The Father’s Love, the Son’s Grace, the Spirit’s Life" number="4">
    <lesson id="week4-day1">
      <title>God’s Person</title>
      <keyVerses>Matt 28:19; 2 Cor 13:14; Luke 11:5-8; Luke 15:20-24</keyVerses>
      <summary>One God in three persons for our experience: love (source), grace (expression), fellowship (transmission); God is intimate and receiving.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>Trinity revealed for dispensing God into us.</point>
        <point>Love, grace, fellowship — one flow for experience.</point>
        <point>Friend and Father: God welcomes us home.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>“Father, Son, Spirit — one God with me now.”</practice>
      <citations>4-1:L1-L13,L13-L33,L33-L76</citations>
    </lesson>

    <lesson id="week4-day2">
      <title>God’s Attributes</title>
      <keyVerses>1 Jn 5:12; 1:5-7; Eph 2:4; Rev 21:23; 22:5</keyVerses>
      <summary>Attributes are God’s inner nature (life, love, light); when expressed in us they become virtues; His life, love, and light are for our walk.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>Attributes vs. virtues — divinity expressed through humanity.</point>
        <point>Only God’s life is true life; His love reaches us in mercy; His light illumines us.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>“Lord, shine; grow Your life in me.”</practice>
      <citations>4-2:L1-L13,L13-L52,L52-L92</citations>
    </lesson>

    <lesson id="week4-day3">
      <title>Holiness</title>
      <keyVerses>Heb 12:10; Ps 89:14; 1 Jn 1:9; Phil 2:13</keyVerses>
      <summary>Holiness is God’s nature shared with us; righteousness is His unshakeable way; the Triune God operates in us.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>Holy = different, saturated with God’s nature.</point>
        <point>Righteousness: our steady ground — confess and be forgiven.</point>
        <point>The Trinity is God acting in us now.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>“God, work in me; make me holy and steady.”</practice>
      <citations>4-3:L1-L18,L31-L78,L78-L114</citations>
    </lesson>

    <lesson id="week4-day4">
      <title>The Definition of God’s Economy</title>
      <keyVerses>Eph 3:9; 2 Cor 13:14</keyVerses>
      <summary>God’s economy = His plan to dispense Himself into us: from the Father, in the Son, through the Spirit.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>Dispensing Himself — mass “sharing” of God to people.</point>
        <point>Love → grace → fellowship: one element in three stages.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>“Father’s love, Son’s grace, Spirit’s fellowship — flow in me.”</practice>
      <citations>4-4:L1-L22,L22-L63</citations>
    </lesson>

    <lesson id="week4-day5">
      <title>From the Father</title>
      <keyVerses>John 1:14,18; Col 1:15,19; 2:9; John 10:30; Isa 9:6</keyVerses>
      <summary>The Father embodied in the Son makes the invisible God accessible; Christ contains seven key ‘elements’ including incarnation, death, resurrection, ascension, enthronement.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>Father becomes approachable in the Son.</point>
        <point>Seven elements in Christ’s person and history.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>“Jesus, reveal the Father to me today.”</practice>
      <citations>4-5:L1-L22,L22-L83</citations>
    </lesson>

    <lesson id="week4-day6">
      <title>Through the Spirit</title>
      <keyVerses>1 Cor 15:45; 2 Cor 3:17; 2 Tim 4:22; 1 Cor 6:17; John 4:24</keyVerses>
      <summary>All that the Father and Son are is transmitted to us in the Spirit of reality; the Spirit is ‘all-inclusive’ and makes us one spirit with the Lord.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>Spirit as transmission: brings God in Christ into us.</point>
        <point>All-inclusive Spirit includes Christ’s humanity, death, resurrection, ascension, enthronement.</point>
        <point>Joined to the Lord — one spirit; freedom and supply.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>Call “O Lord Jesus” and be freshly supplied.</practice>
      <citations>4-6:L1-L27,L27-L83,L83-L131</citations>
    </lesson>
  </series>
</studyGuide>
