<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<studyGuide version="1.1" locale="en">
  <series title="Taste and Breathe the Word" number="3">
    <lesson id="week3-day1">
      <title>The Word of Life</title>
      <keyVerses>John 1:1; 1 John 1:1; John 6:63</keyVerses>
      <summary>The Bible brings us the living Christ; touch Scripture inwardly with your spirit to receive life.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>The Bible is unique — the Word of life.</point>
        <point>Outward (mind) vs. inward (spirit) touching of Scripture.</point>
        <point>Open the Bible to meet the Lord Himself.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>Pray-read John 1:1: “O Lord — the Word is life to me.”</practice>
      <citations>3-1:L1-L13,L31-L60,L60-L83</citations>
    </lesson>

    <lesson id="week3-day2">
      <title>Coming to the Word to “Taste” the Lord</title>
      <keyVerses>1 Pet 2:2-3; Matt 4:4; Jer 15:16; Psa 119:103</keyVerses>
      <summary>We taste Christ by drinking the milk of the Word and eating every word from God.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>The Word is milk and bread for growth.</point>
        <point>Do not take the Bible as mere knowledge; it is life to be eaten.</point>
        <point>Eating the Word becomes joy and strength within.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>Read one verse; whisper “Amen” after each phrase.</practice>
      <citations>3-2:L1-L9,L13-L35,L35-L71,L71-L87</citations>
    </lesson>

    <lesson id="week3-day3">
      <title>Pray-reading the Word</title>
      <keyVerses>Eph 6:17-18; John 6:63</keyVerses>
      <summary>Prepare your heart, then receive the Word by all prayer; the words become Spirit and life.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>Confess and enter fellowship before reading.</point>
        <point>Pray the Scripture itself; many ways to pray-read.</point>
        <point>When words meet prayer, they become Spirit and life.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>Keep eyes on the text; turn each line into short prayers.</practice>
      <citations>3-3:L1-L13,L13-L43,L43-L77,L77-L101</citations>
    </lesson>

    <lesson id="week3-day4">
      <title>The Bible Being God’s Breathing Out</title>
      <keyVerses>2 Tim 3:16; John 5:39-40; John 6:63</keyVerses>
      <summary>Scripture is God’s breathing out; our prayer is breathing in. Come to the Bible to come to Jesus.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>Read prayerfully to breathe in what God has breathed out.</point>
        <point>God’s words are food; eating gives life.</point>
        <point>The Bible is one with the Lord; come to Him for life.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>Breathe in rhythm while reading: inhale “God-breathed,” exhale “life in me.”</practice>
      <citations>3-4:L1-L13,L13-L43,L43-L87</citations>
    </lesson>

    <lesson id="week3-day5">
      <title>Learning to Pray-read with Our Spirit</title>
      <keyVerses>John 15:4,7; Col 3:16; Eph 5:18-19</keyVerses>
      <summary>Let Christ’s words abide in you by pray-reading; this fills you with the Spirit and produces song.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>Christ abides as His words abide in us.</point>
        <point>Strike the Word at the right spot (our spirit) — then fire!</point>
        <point>Filled with the Word, we sing with grace.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>Pray-read John 15:7 three times, then sing a short praise.</practice>
      <citations>3-5:L1-L17,L17-L53,L53-L84</citations>
    </lesson>

    <lesson id="week3-day6">
      <title>The Inward Washing of the Water</title>
      <keyVerses>Eph 5:18,25-26; John 7:38-39</keyVerses>
      <summary>The Word becomes the Spirit in us, washing and transforming us from within over time.</summary>
      <points>
        <point>Filled with the Word → inward washing removes spots and wrinkles.</point>
        <point>Christ settles in our heart; love and clarity grow.</point>
        <point>Long-term pray-reading brings metabolic transformation.</point>
      </points>
      <practice>Muse a verse for 2 minutes; say “Amen” to let the water flow.</practice>
      <citations>3-6:L1-L17,L17-L55,L55-L110</citations>
    </lesson>
  </series>
</studyGuide>
